When I started raising their Kundalini, first only two people got it, naturally.
जब मैंने उनकी कुंडलिनी को ऊपर उठाना शुरू किया, स्वाभाविक रूप से, पहले केवल दो लोगों को ही मिला।
Then so many people got this. So they said, "We too want to have this within us,
फिर इतने सारे लोगों को यह मिला। तो उन्होंने कहा, "हम भी इसे अपने भीतर महसूस करना चाहते हैं,
so can You give us?" I said, "I'll try, I don't know." So, we thought we should
तो क्या आप हमें दे सकतीं हैं?" मैंने कहा, "मैं कोशिश करुँगी, मुझे पता नहीं।" इसलिए, हमने सोचा कि हमें
go into a place which is away from the city. So we were about 25 people.
ऐसी जगह जाना चाहिए जो शहर से दूर हो। तो हम लगभग 25 लोग थे।
I think, 6 or 7 people got their realization. So they told us that, "We are feeling the
मुझे लगता है, 6 या 7 लोगों को उनकी अनुभूति(साक्षात्कार) हुई। तो उन्होंने हमें बताया कि, "हम महसूस कर रहे हैं
cool breeze in our hand and also the cool breeze coming out of fontanel bone area."
हमारे हाथ में शीतल हवा और फॉन्टानेल हड्डी क्षेत्र(तालु भाग) से भी शीतल हवा आ रही है।"
So, I said, "That's it. Now you have to grow in it, you have to watch with a
तो, मैंने कहा, "वही है। अब आपको इसमें विकसित होना, देखना होगा आपको
witness state you should find out what has happened to you." I must say, those days
साक्षी भाव से, पता लगाना चाहिए कि आपके साथ क्या हुआ  है।" मुझे कहना होगा, उन दिनों,
those days people were very, very genuine - they wanted, so it was not just a stunt
उन दिनों लोग बहुत, बहुत सच्चे थे - वे चाहते थे, इसलिए यह सिर्फ एक प्रचार साधन नहीं था।
and so, altogether out of 25, 21 got this.
और इसलिए, कुल मिलाकर 25 में से 21 को यह मिला।